## **HUGH LIM**

- **+65 9797 3571**
- % https://sg.linkedin.com/in/hughlim
- hugh.lim105@gmail.com
- **?** Singapore



## **EXPERIENCES**

#### Manager

#### **PriceWaterhouseCoopers LLP**

□ Dec 2014 - ongoing Singapore

- Provided internal audit in private banking, securities and funds services and treasury to multinational banks
- Manager-in-charge for several internal audit projects to review processes such as risk management, compliance, AML/CFT, credit risk and operations
- Led a team of 2-3 people to provide financial litigation support to internationally-renowned private bank in advising the financial position of derivative instruments worth over US\$ 100 million (AUM)
- Set up Finance function for a government start-up company and managed the funds receipt and utilization over S\$20 million
- Established and implemented Finance and Procurement policies and procedures to ensure alignment and compliance with corporate governance requirements
- Drafted proposals to assist Partners in business development to pitch for new projects ranging from S\$200k to S\$1 million

#### Regional Internal Auditor

#### **Donaldson Filtration (Asia Pacific) Pte. Ltd.**

i Jan 2014 - Nov 2014 ♥ Singapore

- Performed and managed 5 countries (China, India, Hongkong, Singapore and Australia) of internal audit and risk management reviews to evaluate control effectiveness in financial and operational activities
- Identified potential gaps and areas of improvement in stock obsolensence and impairment amounting to S\$2 million and communicated with senior management with regards to the implementation actions

#### Senior Associate

#### **Ernst & Young LLP**

Mov 2012 - Dec 2014 
 Singapore

- Oversaw a team of 4-5 people working on several external audit projects and provided guidance to team members
- Performed financial due diligence on various types of companies in Singapore and China (listed, non-listed and IPO) including trading, manufacturing and construction worth over S\$1 billion of business
- Actively communicated with clients and Partners to manage the expectations, chosen by multiple clients in recurring audit projects due to excellent problem-solving and communication skills

## **ABOUT ME**



**English and Mandarin: Native** 



Bahasa Melayu/ Indonesia: Business proficiency



Art tutor for kids for 2 years



Drawing for 10 years since
Primary school; won multiple
awards from drawing competition



Public speaker: Hosted accounting seminar during university and friends' wedding



Professional in risk, controls and compliance on the weekdays, avid volunteer on the weekends

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Commerce, Accounting and Finance

**Curtin University of Technology** 

<sup>1</sup> 2007 - 2009 **Perth** 

# Certified Practising Accountants

**CPA Australia** 

**2014 - 2016** 

# Unified Examination Certification (UEC)

**Foon Yew High School** 

**2001 - 2006** 

## **EXPERIENCES**

#### **Audit Associate**

#### **Foo Kon Tan Grant Thornton LLP**

• Performed external audit, variance analysis, prepared financial statements for listed, non-listed and IPO clients.

## **VOLUNTEERS**

#### World Vision

#### **Child Sponsor**

Aug 2014 - ongoing

#### Muhammadiyah Welfare Home

#### **Donations and volunteer works**

Jan 2016 - ongoing

#### Lee Ah Mooi Old Age Home

#### **Donations and volunteer works**

May 2015 - ongoing

#### The Soup Kitchen Project

#### **Volunteer works**

Jan 2016 - ongoing

## **MOST PROUD OF**



#### **Proud Investor**

Doubled personal (and my father's) net worth and savings in a span of 4 years through persistent market analysis and timely investments choices.



#### **CFO for 6 months**

Envisioned and established Finance function for a government start-up company. Worked directly with CEO to define financial systems from budget management to IT and HR staffing.



#### Taekwondo Black Belt

Achieved black belt rank in record time (2 years) and won my first sparring championship at the age of 17.

### **REFERRALS**

#### Dr. Tommy Tan, CEO, TC Capital

tommy@tccapital.com

## Lim Kian Giap, Senior Manager, Ernst & Young LLP,

Office number: +65 6535 7777